<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data_science on Drew Howell</title>
    <link>/tags/data_science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data_science on Drew Howell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/data_science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Clustering</title>
      <link>/2021/04/22/clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/04/22/clustering/</guid>
      <description>shiny app that iterates through k-means clustering
refresher on euclidean distance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Logic</title>
      <link>/2021/04/25/bayesian-logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/04/25/bayesian-logic/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Opinion Survey Analysis</title>
      <link>/2021/05/06/student-opinion-survey-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/05/06/student-opinion-survey-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Student Opinion Analysis End-of-semester feedback from students in my &amp;quot;Intro to Data Science&amp;quot; course at ORU. The responses are voluntary and anonymous, and I usually incentivize completion with extra credit, but I still have only gotten around a 70% completion rate since starting the course (about 18 total submissions). If you&#39;re viewing on a phone, it looks better in landscape.
Here&#39;s the script for this table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Parsing with R</title>
      <link>/2021/05/06/text-parsing-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/05/06/text-parsing-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Talk about the text parsing functions. gsub, grepl, grep
workflow: filenames, doc, looping, cleaning, output
use the sos data as an example, maybe grab an innocuous one from work</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Experience of Data Science in Finance</title>
      <link>/2021/05/05/data-science-in-finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/05/05/data-science-in-finance/</guid>
      <description>My Experience of Data Science in Banking My first career job in analytics was at a bank. My first project was to try to replicate a white paper on machine learning for mortgage prepayment predictions. After a lot of time and effort, I failed to replicate the model and ended up with what basically amounted to a linear model (read: an extremely oversimplified version of the one in the paper).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DS Section Nav</title>
      <link>/2021/04/29/ds-section-nav/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/04/29/ds-section-nav/</guid>
      <description>Here is a list of my data science articles in the order I would present them to someone who is unfamiliar with data science.
Data Science Articles  Data Literacy - discussing aspects of data and digital information in general Visualizing Data - how to convey quantitative information Clustering - reveal the inherent &amp;quot;cliques&amp;quot; of rows within your data set The K-means Algorithm - step-by-step visualizations of the algorithm at work Joining Data - methods for joining different data sets into one Bayesianism - why is Thomas Bayes such a big deal?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Literacy</title>
      <link>/2021/04/25/data-literacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/04/25/data-literacy/</guid>
      <description>Intro Data is fundamentally different from information, and information is fundamentally different from knowledge. However, they are related in the sense that knowledge is composed of collected information and information is composed of curated and analyzed data. Since data science is defined as the process of extracting value from data, and what&#39;s valuable is knowledge, we can look at data science as the process of turning data into accurate information, and then into knowledge/insight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joining Data</title>
      <link>/2021/04/22/joining-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/04/22/joining-data/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Sometimes the goal of an analysis requires you to gather data from different sources. And even when you can get by with only using one souce, it could take the form of several separate Excel spreadsheets from the marketing department, or an enterprise-wide data warehouse, for example. Sooner or later, you&#39;ll need to join multiple data sets together.
Imagine that you are analyzing your last year&#39;s worth of exercise data from your fitbit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>